<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Repartee, per se</title>
    <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/categories/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Repartee, per se</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021, Andres Domingo; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20 Years and 6 Degrees</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/20-years-and-6-degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/20-years-and-6-degrees/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/20-years-and-6-degrees/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, it’s a near certainty that we are all within 6 degrees of separation from one of the 2,977 Americans who tragically lost their lives this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have met perhaps a cousin of someone lost who now works in our company, a church member’s granddaughter who never met her grandfather, someone’s brother-in-law who fought in our unit when we proudly volunteered, a friend of a friend whose life was somehow directly touched by the life of someone lost that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of people felt that loss directly, and nothing can change that or make it hurt any less. But we bear that loss as a nation as well, and today we can remember the unity their loss created and honor them rightly. We can teach a new generation of the resilience of the American spirit and the strength we wield when united.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if we remember, if we reflect upon the country we became after the loss of those 2,977 souls 20 years ago and live by that memory - their sacrifice might just save us anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let’s Roll.”&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom Isn&#39;t Free</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
The Cost of Freedom
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. As Americans, that’s a well-understood concept. Our freedoms come at a cost - we have to work for it, fight for it and, yes, sometimes some have died to preserve those freedoms for their countrymen, for their posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think we fail, especially of late, to appreciate the full implications of that statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. But it doesn’t just mean that we might have to wage armed conflict and die to preserve it. What it really implies, and the part that I think many Americans fail to realize, is that statement actually means that we have an extraordinary responsibility. It says less about our actual freedoms, and more about how we use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greater the degree of personal liberty you enjoy, the greater the personal responsibility you have. And that personal responsibility means that sometimes you have to sacrifice or do something that you don’t particularly want to do to preserve liberty for your countrymen, for your posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we could remember that simple fact, perhaps we wouldn’t be so conflicted over mask mandates, vaccine passports, or any other bogeyman some of us use to evade our personal responsibility while over-emphasizing our individual liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. Let’s not leave everything to the military. Let’s all make the sacrifice. Get vaccinated if you are medically able, wear a mask to help stop the spread, and let’s just get this scourge of humanity under control.
Individual liberty and personal responsibility are two sides of the same coin - one cannot exist without the other. Maybe it’s time we bring civics back to the core curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five-Card Monte?</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/five-card-monte/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/five-card-monte/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/five-card-monte/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/five-card-monte/index.en_files/htmlwidgets/htmlwidgets.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/five-card-monte/index.en_files/pymjs/pym.v1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/five-card-monte/index.en_files/widgetframe-binding/widgetframe.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
Four-of-a-kind won’t cut it
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have six presidents. When Joseph Biden took the Oath of Office on January 20, 2021, the United States officially had one current president, and &lt;strong&gt;five living former&lt;/strong&gt; presidents (Donald Trump, Barack Obama, George W Bush, Bill Clinton, and Jimmy Carter). But having so many living presidents isn’t exactly rare - except for a short two-year gap between 2007 and 2009, we’ve had at least 5 presidents (the one current and four living former presidents) ever since George HW Bush took office in January of 1989. That’s 30 out of the last 32 years, and for about 5 of those years, we had 6 with us, just as we have now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not rare, since about 1989. It &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; rare for the entire remaining history of the United States. In fact, it was rare to have five, including the current president. Only at one other time in American history prior to the fall of the Soviet Union did we have a total of six presidents alive, and one of them was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the short interval when Lincoln was inaugurated in March of 1861, and the time that former president John Tyler died at the age of 71 on January 18, 1862, was the last period during which the US saw &lt;em&gt;six&lt;/em&gt; presidents, prior to the 1990s. These were Lincoln, James Buchanan, Franklin Pierce, Millard Fillmore, Martin Van Buren, and the aforementioned Tyler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;font size=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;color: indianred;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Timeline of the US Presidents (Inauguration to Death)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;font size=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;color: cornflowerblue;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drag and zoom on timeline below to change focus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;htmlwidget-1&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;height:600px;&#34; class=&#34;widgetframe html-widget&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;application/json&#34; data-for=&#34;htmlwidget-1&#34;&gt;{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;url&#34;:&#34;index.en_files/figure-html//widgets/widget_timeline.html&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:{&#34;xdomain&#34;:&#34;*&#34;,&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;:false,&#34;lazyload&#34;:false}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]}&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
But sometimes all you have is an Ace-[hole]
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s even more rare to have just one president…this has happened only twice, for a total of about 22 months.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened when Calvin Coolidge shed his mortal coil in January of 1933, leaving only the current president, Herbert Hoover, the sole living member of the Presidents Club. But only two months later, he was joined by the newly inaugurated Franklin D Roosevelt.&lt;/p&gt;
It happened for a second, and much longer time, between when Lyndon B Johnson died in January 1973 and when Gerald Ford took office in August of 1974 following President Nixon’s resignation. It was particularly interesting this time, as the only president was the then-current president, the embattled Richard Nixon. Yes, it was Nixon alone, at the height of his hubris and scandal, facing imminent political and perhaps criminal catastrophe, who represented the Office of the Presidency of the United States.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Data Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.presidentsusa.net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presidential Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disregarding the years of George Washington’s presidency, of course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Settle a Score?</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/to-settle-a-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/to-settle-a-score/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/to-settle-a-score/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
It’s been twenty years, but could it really be true this time?
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a literal score since this war began, and there are now some fighting in it who weren’t alive when it did. It will have scarred &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; generations by the time it is finally over. And that day might actually be within reach.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as with any conflict, there are merits to the effort, and then there are failures. And we have certainly had our share of each as a nation. But an inter-generational war is a failure of imagination - after two decades, some progress must have been made to allow for some other means. But to put this into perspective, there are about 80 million people aged 19 and younger in America. That means that an &lt;strong&gt;entire 25% of the country had not been born when this war started.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/to-settle-a-score/index.en_files/figure-html/vis1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
All’s well that…well, ends.
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Biden has committed to ending this conflict at long last…but we’ve heard this line before. So time will tell if he can succeed where his three predecessors failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, our “nation-building” efforts may not have the greatest success rate, at least in the way that you should consider success. At the same time, I think we may too often forget about where it has succeeded, and at times exceedingly. Perhaps the beacon of triumph is that of South Korea. The US isolated it from Soviet and Chinese influence as much as possible, and went about the years long effort to help build not just a nation, but cultivate a thriving free-market democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe it’s true that America’s history in this respect is not always the exemplar, but she certainly has her moments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Q-Anon Phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/the-qanon-phenomenon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/the-qanon-phenomenon/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/the-qanon-phenomenon/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-new-world-order&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The New World Order&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This QAnon phenomenon is remarkably disconcerting, and some of the symbolism that made its way into the Capitol is an example of how this is a unifying force for our most extreme ideologies, and that it has forced its way into our normal discourse. It is even more concerning that while those that believe in these conspiracy theories, believe them intensely; while those who do not, think them the complete nonsense that they are, and so do not engage in it in any serious way. So these ideas can perpetuate, slowly (or rapidly) increasing their influence relatively unchecked. I’m afraid it might be time that we need to care a little more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the iconography on display at the Capitol riots were symbols of white supremacy movements. The Confederate Battle flag made it into Statuary Hall, which I don’t think has ever happened, at least not in such a visible way. But there were also the Auschwitz references, and the “6M…” nonsense. So not only did we see the white supremacy that was sort of born out of slavery and that particular evolution of racism, but we also saw the more neo-Nazi, fascist sort of white supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also boogaloo symbolism; a group that I don’t think even normally supports authority figures, but they support anarchy, so at least they know what to call that national disgrace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/KekistanVRiechsflagg.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flag of Kekistan and the “Come and Take It” flag were prominent, and are evocative of the Nazi Reichskriegsflagge and the Ansar Ghazwat-ul-Hind flag, respectively. The former is obviously meant to be so, the latter, however, I don’t believe is actually intentional but is reminiscent nonetheless.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Confederate%20with%20M16.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Ansar_Ghazwat-ul-Hind_Flag.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to parse, but we need to take some time to understand, on a cultural and not simply a political level, what is happening. These groups, while having their fair share of overlapping demographics, do not normally meet and work together in the manner that we witnessed. But they have now united under one figurehead and have created an atmosphere that is very unfamiliar in American history – that of living under constant threat of terrorism. Are we headed for an arrangement that is more akin to that of Israel, in which a certain level of terrorism is almost to be expected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This radical fringe movement has, alarmingly, gained such traction that some outspoken adherents of QAnon have been elected to national office. At the same time, the QAnon conspiracy theories that were born and promulgated in America are finding their way into the far-right groups in several European countries, Canada, Australia, Brazil, and others.
After two decades of fighting against radicalized terrorism abroad, I fear that we are on the precipice of exporting our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
