<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Repartee, per se</title>
    <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Repartee, per se</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021, Andres Domingo; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Freedom Isn&#39;t Free</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
The Cost of Freedom
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. As Americans, that’s a well-understood concept. Our freedoms come at a cost - we have to work for it, fight for it and, yes, sometimes some have died to preserve those freedoms for their countrymen, for their posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think we fail, especially of late, to appreciate the full implications of that statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. But it doesn’t just mean that we might have to wage armed conflict and die to preserve it. What it really implies, and the part that I think many Americans fail to realize, is that statement actually means that we have an extraordinary responsibility. It says less about our actual freedoms, and more about how we use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greater the degree of personal liberty you enjoy, the greater the personal responsibility you have. And that personal responsibility means that sometimes you have to sacrifice or do something that you don’t particularly want to do to preserve liberty for your countrymen, for your posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we could remember that simple fact, perhaps we wouldn’t be so conflicted over mask mandates, vaccine passports, or any other bogeyman some of us use to evade our personal responsibility while over-emphasizing our individual liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. Let’s not leave everything to the military. Let’s all make the sacrifice. Get vaccinated if you are medically able, wear a mask to help stop the spread, and let’s just get this scourge of humanity under control.
Individual liberty and personal responsibility are two sides of the same coin - one cannot exist without the other. Maybe it’s time we bring civics back to the core curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Will and Fair Will</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/free-will-and-fair-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/free-will-and-fair-will/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/free-will-and-fair-will/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think the idea of “Free Will” gets complicated by the existence of a Divinely-derived morality. Because it often reduces to a binary question that is largely based on the opinion of the deity that inspired said morality. Is this good, or is this bad, to the deity? I don’t doubt that there may be a God that defines a universal moral truth, to be sure, most of humanity believes this to be true in some way. But I’m not sure if our knowledge of, or even our belief that there is a God that expects us to behave in a certain way, is fully compatible with the idea of Free Will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you provide students with a few major ideas to focus on for a test as most good teachers do, they are entirely free to focus on anything else or nothing at all. But it’s such an obvious failing if a student chooses to ignore the recommendation, with such an obvious consequence that, I would argue, it completely dispels the notion that there is any real “free” choice in the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truest “free will” would be free of any knowledge of, or any perception of, frankly any consequence. No outside expectation would influence your moral compass – just your own intellect, and the society in which you exist. Not that there are no consequences – all the rules can still apply, we just couldn’t know anything about them, or even that they exist.
The Fairness of such a freedom would, however, range from extremely dubious to downright scandalous (which would certainly also put the morality of any deity issuing it into question). So what we get instead is perhaps not entirely Free Will…but maybe it’s pretty fair.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
