<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Repartee, per se</title>
    <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Repartee, per se</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021, Andres Domingo; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20 Years and 6 Degrees</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/20-years-and-6-degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/20-years-and-6-degrees/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/20-years-and-6-degrees/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, it’s a near certainty that we are all within 6 degrees of separation from one of the 2,977 Americans who tragically lost their lives this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have met perhaps a cousin of someone lost who now works in our company, a church member’s granddaughter who never met her grandfather, someone’s brother-in-law who fought in our unit when we proudly volunteered, a friend of a friend whose life was somehow directly touched by the life of someone lost that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of people felt that loss directly, and nothing can change that or make it hurt any less. But we bear that loss as a nation as well, and today we can remember the unity their loss created and honor them rightly. We can teach a new generation of the resilience of the American spirit and the strength we wield when united.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if we remember, if we reflect upon the country we became after the loss of those 2,977 souls 20 years ago and live by that memory - their sacrifice might just save us anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let’s Roll.”&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom Isn&#39;t Free</title>
      <link>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
&lt;script src=&#34;https://repartee-per-se.netlify.app/post/freedom-isn-t-free/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
The Cost of Freedom
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. As Americans, that’s a well-understood concept. Our freedoms come at a cost - we have to work for it, fight for it and, yes, sometimes some have died to preserve those freedoms for their countrymen, for their posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think we fail, especially of late, to appreciate the full implications of that statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. But it doesn’t just mean that we might have to wage armed conflict and die to preserve it. What it really implies, and the part that I think many Americans fail to realize, is that statement actually means that we have an extraordinary responsibility. It says less about our actual freedoms, and more about how we use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greater the degree of personal liberty you enjoy, the greater the personal responsibility you have. And that personal responsibility means that sometimes you have to sacrifice or do something that you don’t particularly want to do to preserve liberty for your countrymen, for your posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we could remember that simple fact, perhaps we wouldn’t be so conflicted over mask mandates, vaccine passports, or any other bogeyman some of us use to evade our personal responsibility while over-emphasizing our individual liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom isn’t free. Let’s not leave everything to the military. Let’s all make the sacrifice. Get vaccinated if you are medically able, wear a mask to help stop the spread, and let’s just get this scourge of humanity under control.
Individual liberty and personal responsibility are two sides of the same coin - one cannot exist without the other. Maybe it’s time we bring civics back to the core curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
